# Mostafa Mohamed Belal

+201211923735 | mostafabelalfci@gmail.com | Nasr City - Cairo - Egypt

https://github.com/Mostafa-Belal2 | linkedin.com/in/mostafa-belal-261523185/

## SUMMARY

A skilled full stack Java developer with +3 years of hands-on experience in designing, modifying, developing, testing, implementing java web applications, and enterprise solutions. I am very interested in the field of software development, and I would appreciate the opportunity to move forward in this field with a great team in a progressive environment.

### **EDUCATION**

College: BSc. in CS, Faculty of Computer and Information Menofiya University, 2018, Very Good Degree.
EXPERIENCE
Full Stack Java Developer at Segmatek (Sep.2020 – Present )
<ul> <li>My responsibilities included architecting, designing, developing of both frontend and backend services. I worked on building multiple services from scratch using Spring stack and Angular.</li> <li>fix client issues &amp; working through timelines with maintaining quality and lifecycle of the project.</li> <li>Full Stack Java Developer at Spectraflare (Sep.2021 – Present )</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>My responsibilities included architecting, designing, developing of both frontend and backend services. I worked on building multiple services from scratch using Spring stack and Angular, JavaFX.</li> <li>fix client issues &amp; working through timelines with maintaining quality and lifecycle of the project.</li> <li>Java Backend Developer at Senior Steps (Jan.2020 – Jun.2020)</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>Implement new services using Servlets , JSP , JSTL , Basic JSF , Hibernate , Web Service (         RESTful API,SOAP Web Service)</li> <li>□ Spring Core ,Spring Data ,Spring MVC ,Spring RESTful API , Spring Boot , Mysql, Design Pattern ,         Solid principles</li> <li>□ fix client issues &amp; working through timelines with maintaining quality and lifecycle of the project.</li> <li>Android Developer Internship (Jun.2018 – Oct.2018)</li> </ul>
□ Customizing , modifying standard modules Develop the Project structure and fixing bugs Java Developer Internship (Jul.2017 – Sep.2017)
□ Learning and practicing java, design patterns, data structures and algorithms in real world apps
Experienced In: Java (SE/EE), Hibernate/JPA, Spring Core, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Spring Data, Spring Cloud, Spring Security, Docker, Jenkins, JSF/ PrimeFaces,, JSP, Angular 2+, HTML/CSS, SQL, NOSQL, MySQL, Oracle DB, MongoDB, Redis, Git, Jenkins, Maven, RESTful, JavaScript, Flyway.
Software Engineering: OOP, MVC, Microservices, Design Patterns, Database Design.
Languages: Very Good English. Native Arabic.

### **PROJECTS**

### E-Care -Telecom Egypt (WE).

It's a telecommunication e-care system for telecom Egypt .
We revamp its frontend with new angular structure and design.

<ul> <li>Updated and added new features in backend.</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>I was involved as full stack developer.</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>Technologies: Spring Boot, Spring Data, Spring REST, Spring Security, JPA, Oracle DB, angular11.</li> </ul>
☐ The link of the project online <u>Login (te.eg)</u>
E-Care – Mali (Malittel):
<ul> <li>It's a telecommunication e-care system for Malittel in Mali,</li> <li>User can recharge, see call history, view the consumption, subscribe to offers and services and do other different telecom-related functionalities.</li> </ul>
<ul><li>□ I was involved as full stack developer.</li><li>□ Technologies: Spring Boot, Spring Data, Spring REST, Spring Security, JPA, Oracle DB</li></ul>
PharmaClinic:
<ul> <li>It's a pharma clinic system for to serve the doctor and the patient,</li> <li>The system manage the appointments,invoices,history of the doctor and the patient,</li> <li>I was involved as full stack developer.</li> <li>Technologies: Spring Boot, Spring Data, Spring REST, JPA, Oracle DB, Angular, Java FX</li> </ul>
Ordering Food App :
☐ Application for ordering food online like otlob. The project consists of 3 application:
Consumer app: mobile app and web app.
Provider app: a web app.
Admin app: a web app.
<ul> <li>I was involved mainly in the backend.</li> <li>Technologies: Servlet, Jsp, Hibernate, Spring Boot, Spring Data, Spring REST, JPA, MySQL DB</li> </ul>
☐ GitHub Repository: <a href="https://github.com/Mostafa-Belal2/Ordering_food_online_web_App.">https://github.com/Mostafa-Belal2/Ordering_food_online_web_App.</a>
StoreApp:
☐ Application for buying and selling of products.
☐ I was involved mainly in the backend here as the front was mainly mobile-based.
$\hfill\Box$ Technologies: Spring Boot, Spring Data, Spring REST, JPA, MySQL DB .
☐ <b>GitHub Repository</b> : <a href="https://github.com/Mostafa-Belal2/springboot">https://github.com/Mostafa-Belal2/springboot</a> storeapp.